mofa.go.jp 2006-06-15

# MOFA: Privacy Policy

Top > Privacy Policy 

Official Website of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Japan

### 1\. Basic premise

At the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (hereinafter referred to as "the Ministry"), we are collecting information from everyone using the Official Website of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (hereinafter referred to as "the Site") in areas necessary to the smooth operation of the services (such as information provision by the homepage and the solicitation of opinions) provided by the Site. Information acquired will be handled appropriately within the scope of the purposes of use.

### 2\. Scope of information acquisition

(1) We automatically collect and store Internet domain names, IP addresses, information about access to the Site (i.e., the date and time you access the Site and the pages you visit) and so on. However, we do not use a cookie (information transmitted from the server to the user's browser and stored on the user's computer in order for the server to identify users). 

(2) At the "Feedback" and "News Letter" corners, users are able to send their comments to the Ministry. We also ask users of What's New Mail Service to register their e-mail address, and optionally gender, age range, occupation, and country they live in.

### 3\. Purposes of use

(1) The information acquired in 2. (1) will be used as a reference for the smooth operation of the service provided by the Site.

(2) The comments collected in 2. (2) will be used as a reference in future policymaking. Email addresses will be used to reply to. Other optional items will be used as reference information.

### 4\. Limitations on use and provision

At the Ministry, except in cases of legal disclosure requests, cases of illegal access, threats and other unlawful acts or other special reasons, the information acquired will not be used by ourselves for any purposes other than those described in 3., nor will it be provided to any third party. However, statistical information regarding access to the Site or information on users' attributes may be made public.

### 5\. Measures to ensure security

The Ministry is taking the measures necessary to manage acquired information appropriately to prevent the leakage, loss or destruction of acquired information.

### 6\. Disclosure of personal information

We do not collect names, birth dates and other information able to identify individuals on the Site. Therefore, we do not respond to requests for disclosure of personal information by contributors to "Feedback" or "News Letter."

### 7\. Scope of application

This privacy policy applies only to the Site.

#### Contact details:

Webmaster  
Public Diplomacy Planning Division, Ministry of Foreign Affairs  
Kasumigaseki 2-2-1, Chiyoda-ku, Tokyo 100-8919, Japan
